Arshdeep Sekhon



arshsekhon.com

arshs3khon@gmail.com

in arsh-sekhon

arshsekhon

Summary -

Full-Stack Developer with **2+ years of industry experience** developing enterprise-scale software.

Skills

Programming Languages: Python, JavaScript, Java, C#, C++ Cloud Platforms: AWS, GCP, Cloud Foundry, OpenStack

Other: ReactJS, NextJS, Bash, Linux

DBs: DynamoDB, SQLServer, Postgres

DevOps: Jenkins, Docker, K8s (basics)

ML/DL: Pandas, Numpy, PyTorch, Keras etc.

Experience -

SAP Concur Travel Profile, Vancouver, Canada | Software Engineer

August 2021-Present

- Architected and developed a highly scalable profile edit tracking system, which enabled a lowered request response times by ~80% of the original.
- Designed a mechanism to off-load read/write traffic from a SQL Server to DynamoDB while ensuring eventually consistency between them, enabling a gradual migration of DB.
- Re-implemented a VBS based legacy system and integrated it into a cloud based microservice (NestJS + TS).
- Developed solutions to assist with cross-region migration of several microservices.

SAP LX Labs, Vancouver, Canada | Cloud Platform Services Developer

May 2019 – July 2021

- Designed the architecture & drove the development of a microservice (Node)S+Typescript, Kubernetes) to detect translatability issues in the product UI, saving ~20-25 mins of employee time/issue.
- Spearheaded the development of automated checks for insensitive terms (NodeJS+Typescript), lowering the risk of such terms making to production by ~70-80%.
- Pioneered the development of several automation features saving users ~1.25 hours/day.

Think Muse Media Ltd., Surrey, Canada | Full-Stack Developer

Jan 2019-Apr 2019

- Designed and developed a CRM system (FileMaker + Python) to automate 60-70% of the client's 10-step ordering & invoicing process and cut the operational cost by 20%.
- Lead the development of websites like <u>AlwaysAndForeverWeddings.ca</u>, <u>AdelaideDesign.ca</u>, <u>ThinkMuse.ca</u>.

SAP LX Labs, Vancouver, Canada | Software Developer (Coop)

May 2018-Dec 2018

- Piloted the design and development of a new secure file replication service that reduced transfer latency from 6+ hours to 5-10 mins.
- Developed new features for Project Management System (C# + Java + JS) used at the organizational level.

Education —

Bachelors of Computing Science | University of the Fraser Valley

Jan 2017 – Jan 2022

- Concentration in Artificial Intelligence and Data Mining ~ Major GPA: 4.33/4.33 -- Overall GPA: 4.28/4.33
- UFV Academic Scholarship, Int'l Students Endowment Scholarship, Int'l Student Academic Excellence Award

Other Achievements —

Winner - SAP iXp Hackathon Fall 2018: Developed an intelligent enterprise skill-sharing social platform. Runner Up - SAP iXp Hackathon Summer 2019: Developed a style assistant app for a reputed clothing brand. Runner Up - SAP iXp Hackathon Summer 2018: Developed a video analysis tool to analyze drone footage.